Guide to the Van Ness-Philip Family Papers 1711-1963 (bulk 1711-1945) MS 653
New-York Historical Society
- Series X. Worthington Family
  - Journal/account book, with hair clipping, undated (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal for Sunday use, Mrs. Elizabeth Worthington, 1876 (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Botanical journal and dictionary, undated (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, Second year in Europe, 1855-1857 (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, undated (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Scrapbook containing dried flowers, calling cards and correspondence, 1855-1857 (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal of poetry, drawing and dried leaves, undated (Box 89, Folder unknown container)
  - Printed material, cards, calendars, booklets, undated (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Journal, Eliza S. Phillip, 1854 (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1875 (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1863 (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Journal, 1865 (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Printed material, Nellie's New Year's Vision, 1874 (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Printed material, Crowning Blessings, A Selection of Poems by Eleanor Grant, undated (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Printed material, The Blood of Jesus, undated (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Printed material, Biographical Sketches of James A. Garfield and Chester A. Arthur, undated (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
  - Printed material, Eulogy on General Grant, 1885 (Box 90, Folder unknown container)
- Series XI. Oversize Materials
  This series contains oversize material consisting mostly of Herman Hoffman Philip's commissions, ca. 1905-37 and signed by Presidents T. Roosevelt, Taft, Harding, Coolidge, Hoover, F.D. Roosevelt. The series also contains comissions of John Van Ness Philip (d. 1949) signed by President McKinley.
  - Commissions, circa 1905-1937 (Folder 1)
- Series XII. Genealogy
  This series contains genealogical information of the Van Ness family, as well as clippings and mausoleum information, such as the deed and cemetery plot. There are also files of the Philip and Worthington family genealogies that contain estate information and obituaries.
  - Van Ness, undated (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Investigation of Van Ness Genealogy in the Netherlands by John P. Van Ness, Coat of arms, 1845 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Van Ness, undated (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - John Peter Van Ness, Marcia Burns and other, newspaper clippings, undated (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Van Ness Mausoleum, undated, 1843, 1867-1871 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Van Ness Mausoleum, deed and cemetery plot, 1872-1877 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Philip, undated (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Philip, undated (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Re: Henry W. Phillips Revolutionary claim, 1832 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Hoffman family, Martin Hoffman Philip, undated (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Catherine Philip, William H. Philip, Hoffman Philip, John V. N. Philip, undated (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Van Ness-Philip, "Talavera" at Claverack, undated (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Philip, obituaries of William H., Eliza W., Elizabeth W. Philip Stark (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Worthington (Box 91, Folder 14)